Multiple components match node with tag name.
Multiple components match node with tag name.
When you encounter this error, it means two or more components use the same element name.
当你遇到本错误时，意味着有两个或更多组件使用了相同的元素名
The element selectors of all components within an ngModule
同一个 ngModule 中的所有组件，其元素选择器
must be unique because when there's a name collision, Angular
必须是唯一的。因为如果有名字冲突，Angular 就没办法
has no way of knowing which component to render in the template.
知道应该在模板中渲染哪一个组件
Let's take a look at a simple reproduction and quick fix in the code.
我们来看一个简单的错误重现，并且在代码中快速修复它
We have an icon component with a selector name of mat-icon.
我们有一个选择器为 mat-icon 的图标组件
The component has been declared with that selector in the
该组件在 AppComponent 的模板中使用此选择器声明过了
app component template, but when we attempt to\h run the app, we get the error.
但是当我们试图运行此应用时却出错了
Multiple components match node with tag name mat-icon your
因为多个组件都能匹配标签名为 mat-icon 的节点
IDE should be able to catch the error in advance.
高级点的 IDE 能够捕获本错误
Notice how when we Hover over the red underline, we get the
注意，当我们悬浮在红色下划线上方时，我们得到了反馈
feedback that more than one component matched on this element.
说是多于一个组件匹配此元素。
In addition, it tells us exactly which classes are in conflict.
另外，它还会告诉我们具体是哪些类发生了冲突
In this case, the mat-icon and the icon component.
在这里是 mat-icon 和 IconComponent
Alternatively, we can debug from the error in the browser
另外，我们可以在浏览器控制台中的错误开始调试
console. Find the link to the template in the stack trace
在错误堆栈中找到该模板的链接
to determine which line of code cause the issue.
以确定代码中的哪一行导致了这个问题
Then we need to figure out which two components share the same selector.
然后，我们还要找出哪两个组件共享了同一个选择器
The first technique you might try is a global search in VS code.
第一种技巧是尝试使用 VS Code 的全局搜索功能
Use Control Shift F to bring up the search bar and look for
使用 Control Shift F 来调出搜索栏，并且查找
any component files that use that selector name.
使用了此选择器名的任意文件
If you have two conflicting components in your code base,
如果你的代码中有两个冲突的组件
simply rename one of them.
只要把其中一个改名就可以了
However, in this demo, we only have one match, and that means
不过，在这个例子中，我们只找到了一个，这意味着
the collision is caused by a third party library.
此冲突是第三方库导致的
Because you likely don't have control over the name of a
因为你无法控制第三方库中的组件名
Your only option is to rename your local component.
所以你唯一的选择是把你的本地组件改名
Notice how when we rename mat-icon to app-icon, the error goes away.
注意，当我们把 mat-icon 改为 app-icon 时，错误消失了
Now, there are a couple of best practices that we can follow
你可以遵循一些最佳实践
to prevent this error from ever happening.
来避免发生此类错误
Selectors should always be formatted.
选择器应该遵循特定的格式
In Kebab case, even though it is possible to use a single
也就是中线格式。虽然你可以用单个单词作为选择器
word as a selector, it's generally better to use a consistent
但一般来说最好还是使用一组固定的字符作为前缀
When you use the Angular CLI, it will prefix your component names with 'app'.
当你使用 Angular CLI 时，它会使用 app 作为你组件的前缀
By default, this convention makes it easy to distinguish
默认情况下，这种规约便于区分
which components are local to your code base and which components
你自己代码中的本地组件和那些来自
Another best practice that can help here is one component per file.
另一个有帮助的最佳实践是把每个组件放在一个文件中
When you have one component per file, the file name generally
当你在每个文件中都有一个组件时，文件名通常与
corresponds to the selector name, which makes it more difficult
选择器名称一一对应，这样你代码中的两个组件就
to end up with two components in your code base that share a selector name.
很难共享同一个选择器名
Let's go ahead and recap.
我们来回顾一下。
When you encounter the multiple components match node with
当你遇到 the multiple components match node with tag name 错误时
tag name error, you have a name collision between two or
说明在两个或多个组件中存在着名字冲突
more components, which will likely require you to change
这通常需要你在一个本地组件中修改
the selector name in one of your local components.
此选择器名称
Make sure to follow best practices to avoid issues like this
确保遵循一些最佳实践，来消除此类错误
and refer to the Angular Style Guide and the official documentation for additional details.
欲知详情，请参阅 Angular 官方文档中的风格指南